Baptiste NIVIERE

WEB DEVELOPER

- baptiste.niviere@gmail.com
- 1016 Masonic avenue San Francisco, CA 94117
- 4152167538
- % baptisteniviere.com

Computer skills

Language Proficiency

- Drupal (9/8/7), Wordpress
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Less. Sass
- PHP, ReactJs, AngularJs
- MySQL, SQL

Development tools Grunt, Gulp, Git, Webpack

Environments / Hosting Lando, Mamp Pantheon, Acquia

Software Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Craft

Assets

Collaborative Eager and enthusiastic team player capable of working crossfunctionally across departments

Time management Ability to manage multiple projects and deadlines simultaneously, prioritizing milestones to ensure on-time delivery

Languages

ENGLISH: Fluent

FRENCH: Fluent

Profile

Web Developer with extensive knowledge in Web technologies and standards. Quick study with ability to implement new skills in a short period of time. I specialize in Drupal, and am very familiar with its API, modules and theming practices.

Work experience

Since April 2020

Developer

Judicial Court of California San Francisco, CA

- Large scale multisite migration / implementation
- Integration of design system into Drupal 8 themes

From February 2018 to November 2019

Developer

The Savage Bureau San Francisco, CA

- Responsible for the maintenance and development of new features on a large scale Drupal 8 platform (REST api)
- Build high profile websites using latest Frontend technologies

From November 2017 to February 2018

Developer (Contract)

BriteLite San Francisco, CA

- Lead development of B2C website (Drupal 8)
- Spearhead strategic initiative to launch websites at high cadence

From March 2011 to July 2017

Lead Developer

Project6 Design Emeryville, CA

- Built over 40 websites using mostly Drupal
- Migrated large websites from Drupal 7 to 8, and Drupal 6 to 8
- Led UX recommendations and optimizations

From August 2015 to November 2017

Co-Founder & Lead Developer

Spiraler San Francisco - Paris

- Led the ideation, development and launch of an online bartering platform
- Pitched and prospected international investors

2014

Teacher / Mentor (Contract)

ESCEN San Francisco, CA

- Taught Drupal & Drupal Commerce advanced classes to IT & **Business students**
- Mentored graduate students through finals

Education

From 2009 to 2011 Master Degree of Computer Sciences

SUPINFO - DOMINICAN UNIVERSITY San Francisco &

Montreal

From 2005 to 2008 Bachelor Degree of Computer Sciences

Paris 5 Descartes Paris